investor.co.id 2019-09-04

# 

##  [Privacy Policy](https://www.investor.co.id/privacy-policy/)

**The Jakarta Globe Privacy Policy**

**INTRODUCTION:**

This Privacy Policy describes how PT Jakarta Globe Media (“Jakarta Globe,” “us” or “we”), publisher of the Jakarta Globe, will collect and use your personally identifiable information (“PII”) (that is — your full name, email address, mailing address, telephone number, or credit card number) as well as data that can, under certain circumstances, indirectly lead to PII (“Related Data”).

This Policy applies to PII and Related Data received by us from: (a) consumers who provide us with information in connection with their subscriptions to Indonesian print editions of the Jakarta Globe, and (b) consumers when they visit, register or subscribe to the online editions of the Jakarta Globe and related services or sites that link to this Privacy Policy such as thejakartaglobe.com and its related services.

From time to time Jakarta Globe may revise this Privacy Policy. If we make revisions that change the way we collect or use your PII or Related Data, those changes will be posted in this Privacy Policy and the effective date will be noted at the beginning of the Policy. Therefore, you should review it periodically so that you are up to date on our most current policies and practices. If we make material changes to our practices regarding use of your PII or Related Data, your PII and Related Data will continue to be governed by the Privacy Policy under which it was subject prior to those changes, unless you have been provided notice of, and have not objected to, the changes.

**INFORMATION THAT WE COLLECT:**

Generally. When you subscribe to our products or services, we collect PII and Related Information from you. We also may collect PII and Related Information from you when you contact us about your subscriptions or participate in activities like: our resume database; job searches; forums; message boards; chats; submitting a letter to the editor; creating a community profile; rating, tagging and commenting on articles; or surveys, sweepstakes, contests, or games. When you visit our web sites, we automatically collect non PII such as IP addresses and web site usage information from you.

We do not, however, knowingly collect PII from children under the age of eighteen.

Sometimes we collect personally identifiable information from consumers in manual format or off-line, for example via a post card or subscription form. Providing detailed notice in those situations often proves impractical, so consumers will instead be provided with a short notice that describes how to obtain the full text of this Policy and other relevant information from us.

When you provide PII to us, we will make sure you are informed about the types of uses we will make of the information to the extent it is being used in a manner that differs from what is allowed pursuant to this Privacy Policy.

Cookies. Cookies are small bits of information that our web sites place on the hard drive of your computer. We use cookies to, among other things, facilitate our login processes; allow you to personalize and store your settings; collect usage information; determine our total audience size and traffic; and help us improve our sites by measuring which areas are of greatest interest to users.

Third party advertisements displayed on our sites may also contain cookies set by Internet advertising companies or advertisers. We do not control these cookies and visitors to our web sites should check the privacy policy of the advertiser to see whether and how it uses cookies. (See the “Notice” section below for more information on third party advertisements).

You can set the browser on your computer to warn you each time a cookie is being sent, block third party cookies or block all cookies. However, by blocking all cookies you may not have access to certain features on our web sites.

We also use web beacons (invisible images often referred to as pixel tags or clear GIFs) on our sites in order to recognize users and assess traffic patterns, and we include web beacons and cookies in our e-mail messages, including newsletters, in order to count how many e-mail messages have been opened.

When you view an ad for our publications on other sites, our third-party advertising company may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. We and our advertising partners may also use web beacons (invisible images often referred to as pixel tags or clear GIFs) to note which pages you visit after viewing our ads. The information that is collected through the use of these images is not personally identifiable and is used only to track response to our advertising efforts.

We may use cookies and similar tools to relate your use of our web sites to PII obtained from you or a reputable third party. For example, if you’ve asked us to send you information about our upcoming products or promotions, cookie and/or click stream data about your activities on our web sites may allow us to limit the materials we send you to items we think you will find interesting, based on your prior online activities and preferences. However, if we wish to combine your personal and cookie or click stream information in this manner, we will obtain your express affirmative consent.

**NOTICE:**

Third Party Web Sites. Our web sites link to web sites operated by other companies. Some of these third party sites may be co-branded with a Jakarta Globe logo, even though they are not operated or maintained by us.

We’re not responsible for the privacy practices of web sites operated by third parties that are linked to or integrated with our sites or for the privacy practices of third party Internet advertising companies. Once you’ve left our site via such a link or by clicking on an advertisement, you should check the applicable privacy policy of the third party or advertiser site to determine how they will handle any PII they collect from you.

Our web sites may also be linked to sites operated by companies affiliated with us (i.e., that are part of the larger Lippo Group (“Affiliated Companies”). Although all Affiliated Companies adhere to the Jakarta Globe’s corporate Privacy Principles, visitors to those Affiliated Company sites should still refer to their separate privacy policies and practices, which may differ in some respects from this Privacy Policy.

**USE: HERE’S HOW WE USE PII**

Generally. We may use information in the following ways:

For the purposes for which you specifically provided it including, without limitation, to enable us to process and fulfill your subscription or other requests.

To send you information about your relationship or transactions with us.

To notify you about our products, services, and special offers.

To otherwise contact you with information that we believe will be of interest to you.

To enhance or develop features, products and services.

To provide advertisers and other third parties with aggregate information about our subscribers, web site user base and usage patterns.

To allow us to personalize the content and advertising that you and others see on our web sites.

To allow other select companies to send you promotional materials about their products and services (that is, unless you’ve told us not to do so (see Choice below).

Information about your activities on our sites and other non-personally identifiable information about you may be used to limit the online ads you encounter to those we believe are consistent with your interests.

We may combine the information that we collect from you with information that you provide to us in connection with your use of other Dow Jones products, services and web sites, or information we collect from third parties.

**SHARING YOUR INFORMATION**

Except as set forth herein, or if we inform you otherwise at the time of data collection, we will not share your PII or Related Data outside of Jakarta Globe.

Affiliates: We may share your PII with companies that are affiliated with us, that is, are part of the Lippo Group of companies.

Service Providers: We may use other companies to perform services including, without limitation, facilitating some aspects of our web sites, sending e-mail, fulfilling purchase requests, delivering subscriptions, serving, customizing or delivering marketing or ads, and auditing. These other companies may be supplied with or have access to your PII and Related Data solely for the purpose of providing these services to us or on our behalf.

Special Circumstances: There may be instances when we may disclose PII or Related Data without providing you with a choice in order to protect the legal rights of Jakarta Globe, other companies within Lippo Group or their employees, agents and contractors; to protect the safety and security of visitors to our web sites; to protect against fraud or for risk management purposes; or to comply with the law or legal process. In addition, if Jakarta Globe sells all or part of its business or makes a sale or transfer of assets or is otherwise involved in a merger or business transfer, we may transfer your PII to a third party as part of that transaction.

Corporate, Third-Party, and Student Subscriptions: If your subscription (whether through a print or online version) is provided in whole or in part by your employer or other third party, we may notify the provider when you access or use your subscription. If you have a student subscription associated with a professor or school, we may notify your professor or school to confirm your subscription, access or use. When providing these notices, we may reveal limited amounts of your personally identifiable information such as your name or email address.

Third Party Promotional Offers: If you subscribe to our print publications, we may share your contact information with other companies whose products and services may be of interest to you. While many of our subscribers appreciate receiving offerings from these companies, if you prefer that we do not share your information for this purpose, please see “Choice” for instructions on how to tell us not to share your information. If you subscribe solely to our online publications, we will not sell, rent, swap, or authorize any third party to use your personally identifiable information for such party’s own marketing purposes, unless you choose in advance to have your personally identifiable information shared for this purpose.

Social Network and Interactive Tools: Certain features on our web sites give you an opportunity to interact with others and us. These may include forums, message boards, chats, submitting a letter to the editor, creating community profiles, and rating, tagging and commenting on articles. When you use these features you should be aware that any information you submit, including your name, location and e-mail address, may be publicly available to others. We are not responsible for any information you choose to submit through these interactive features.

When an individual chooses to post information that will be publicly disclosed, he or she is responsible for ensuring that such information conforms to all local data protection laws. We are not responsible under any data protection laws for user posted information.

Non PII: Anonymous click stream, number of page views calculated by pixel tags, and aggregated demographic information may also be shared with our advertisers and business partners.

**CHOICE: WE WILL PROVIDE YOU WITH CHOICES ABOUT THE USE OF YOUR PII**

You must update your preferences for each of our publications separately, as indicated below:

To unsubscribe to any of our products or to remove your PII from application to other Lippo Group companies, third parties or any other source, please contact our customer care atsubscription.services@thejakartaglobe.com or call +62 21 2995 7555. Our Subscription Management staff will be happy to service your needs and the Jakarta Globe will make all reasonable, within the limits of laws applicable to this process, to protect your PII.

**SECURITY: WE PROTECT THE SECURITY OF PII**

We use commercially reasonable administrative, technical, personnel and physical measures to safeguard PII and Related Data in our possession against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure or modification.

**DATA RETENTION**

We retain your information for as long as necessary to permit us to use it for the purposes that we have communicated to you and comply with applicable law or regulations.

**TRANSFER TO OTHER COUNTRIES**

Your information may be stored and processed in Indonesia or any other country where Jakarta Globe has facilities, and by subscribing to and/or using our publications, you consent to the transfer of information outside of your country.

**REMEDIES AND COMPLIANCE: HOW TO CONTACT US ABOUT PRIVACY CONCERNS**

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about our Privacy Policy, you may contact us at subscription.services@thejakartaglobe.com or call at +62 21 2995 7555.

**YOUR PRIVACY IS IMPORTANT TO US**
